<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>a maxCohen journal</title>
  <subtitle>maxCohen&#39;s journal with fun for the whole family.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://ohpoopy.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://ohpoopy.com/"/>
  <id>https://ohpoopy.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>maxCohen</name>
    <email>abc@senseantisense.com</email>
  </author>
  
  <entry>
    <title>1 Corinthians 3:7 | NIV</title>
    <link href="/2020/i-corinthians-37/"/>
    <updated>Sun Jan 05 2020 18:00:00 GMT-0600 (Central Standard Time)</updated>
    <id>/2020/i-corinthians-37/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;6 January 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So neither the one who plants nor the one who waters is anything, but only God, who makes things grow.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What I See</title>
    <link href="/2020/what-i-see/"/>
    <updated>Sun Feb 02 2020 18:00:00 GMT-0600 (Central Standard Time)</updated>
    <id>/2020/what-i-see/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;3 February 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to observe. To see what is going on around me. What I see is written below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I tell you this, and insist on it in the Lord, that you must no longer live as the Gentiles do, in the futility of their thinking. They are darkened in their understanding and separated from the life of God because of the ignorance that is in them due to the hardening of their hearts. Having lost all sensitivity, they have given themselves over to sensuality so as to indulge in every kind of impurity, and they are full of greed. (Ephesians 4:17-19 | NIV)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Mesh Lightning Talks: Sarantaporo.gr</title>
    <link href="/2020/mesh-lightningtalks-sarantaporo.gr/"/>
    <updated>Wed Feb 05 2020 18:00:00 GMT-0600 (Central Standard Time)</updated>
    <id>/2020/mesh-lightningtalks-sarantaporo.gr/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;6 February 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=58TnEOQVSwQ&amp;amp;list=PLx7_J32Ys60cAmBbdDtx1-THpDU4XbtdV&amp;amp;index=14&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sarantaporo.gr/en/&quot;&gt;Sarantaporo Project Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/58TnEOQVSwQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Time You Have (In JellyBeans)</title>
    <link href="/2020/the-time-you-have-in-jelly-beans/"/>
    <updated>Tue Feb 11 2020 18:00:00 GMT-0600 (Central Standard Time)</updated>
    <id>/2020/the-time-you-have-in-jelly-beans/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;12 February 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BOksW_NabEk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>2 Timothy 3</title>
    <link href="/2020/ii-timothy-3/"/>
    <updated>Wed Feb 19 2020 18:00:00 GMT-0600 (Central Standard Time)</updated>
    <id>/2020/ii-timothy-3/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;2 February 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But mark this: There will be terrible times in the last days. People will be lovers of themselves, lovers of money, boastful, proud, abusive, disobedient to their parents, ungrateful, unholy, without love, unforgiving, slanderous, without self-control, brutal, not lovers of the good, treacherous, rash, conceited, lovers of pleasure rather than lovers of God— having a form of godliness but denying its power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have nothing to do with such people. (2 Timothy 3:1-5 | NIV)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>2 Timothy 4:3-5</title>
    <link href="/2020/ii-timothy-4/"/>
    <updated>Wed Feb 19 2020 18:00:00 GMT-0600 (Central Standard Time)</updated>
    <id>/2020/ii-timothy-4/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;20 February 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the time will come when people will not put up with sound doctrine. Instead, to suit their own desires, they will gather around them a great number of teachers to say what their itching ears want to hear. They will turn their ears away from the truth and turn aside to myths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you, keep your head in all situations, endure hardship, do the work of an evangelist, discharge all the duties of your ministry.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Remembrance</title>
    <link href="/2020/remembrance/"/>
    <updated>Mon Mar 02 2020 18:00:00 GMT-0600 (Central Standard Time)</updated>
    <id>/2020/remembrance/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;3 March 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romanticizing about the past can be comforting and has both its pros and cons. Hearing from the past can give great comfort, flashbacks to what we think were simpler times, and that hit of nostalgia is pleasant. What&#39;s frustrating is not remembering clear enough whether it was a simpler time. The memories are clouded from that much detail. The sensations are there from what you are listening too, but the pain that must have been there during the same time period of life, not necessarily from the experience of the sound (or smell or visual), must have been too. Perhaps one should take it as it is, something happily remembered. And be thankful that the pain isn&#39;t remembered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Inspired by &amp;quot;The Radiant City&amp;quot; by Jóhann Jóhannsson.)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Are you ready for martyrdom?</title>
    <link href="/2020/martyrdom/"/>
    <updated>Mon Mar 02 2020 18:00:01 GMT-0600 (Central Standard Time)</updated>
    <id>/2020/martyrdom/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;3 March 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/journal/2020/beheading_of_st_john_the_baptist.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Beheading of Saint John the Baptist&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&amp;quot;The Beheading of Saint John the Baptist&amp;quot; by Giovanni di Paolo)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Rise of Open Source Communities in China</title>
    <link href="/2020/the-rise-of-open-source-communities-in-china/"/>
    <updated>Mon Mar 02 2020 18:02:00 GMT-0600 (Central Standard Time)</updated>
    <id>/2020/the-rise-of-open-source-communities-in-china/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;3 March 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RFjIBM0TR7U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Two Lungs of Making Websites</title>
    <link href="/2020/the-two-lungs-of-making-websites/"/>
    <updated>Tue Mar 03 2020 18:00:00 GMT-0600 (Central Standard Time)</updated>
    <id>/2020/the-two-lungs-of-making-websites/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;4 March 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two lungs to making websites: User Experience and Content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you take one away you still have a website, but like breathing with just one lung life is much more difficult. Everything stems from those two items. They both have many parts but both are needed for a great website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lists give an example of how it can be divided between groups. Many terms came from Jesse James Garrett&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jjg.net/elements/&quot;&gt;The Elements of User Experience&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content Requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy Writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site Objectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User Needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;User Experience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accessibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functional Specifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interaction Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interface Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigation Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance (which determines technology used)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>My Personal Information</title>
    <link href="/2020/my-personal-information/"/>
    <updated>Tue Mar 03 2020 18:00:01 GMT-0600 (Central Standard Time)</updated>
    <id>/2020/my-personal-information/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;4 March 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received an unsolicited invite today from an individual to join a discussion on a third party corporate site. I went to the site and there was my real name. Without being asked, my personal information is shared with a company I have no desire to have said information shared with. It fascinates me that people don&#39;t just ask before doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I logged in and deactivated my account. Nope, can&#39;t delete it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you do not understand my concern, please go to your local library and find a book on 20th century history. One concerning Europe and/or the United States of America should do nicely.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Future of Ham Radio</title>
    <link href="/2020/the-future-of-ham-radio/"/>
    <updated>Tue Mar 10 2020 19:00:00 GMT-0500 (Central Daylight Time)</updated>
    <id>/2020/the-future-of-ham-radio/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;11 March 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After years of not being in the hobby of ham radio I&#39;ve gotten a bit of an interest in it again. And after all those years the myth of the future of ham radio is still &amp;quot;the youth&amp;quot;. (Well, it&#39;s now the future and that has been the battle cry for decades, how&#39;s it going?) The solution is that the future of ham radio is to work as a community to support each other, regardless of age or any other discriminatory agenda. The whole &amp;quot;youth are our future&amp;quot; is keeping so many others out of the hobby. When a new person comes into ham radio there is not as much help nor interest in helping them if they are out of childhood. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>To Give Up</title>
    <link href="/2020/to-give-up/"/>
    <updated>Wed Mar 18 2020 19:00:00 GMT-0500 (Central Daylight Time)</updated>
    <id>/2020/to-give-up/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;19 March 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At what point is it OK to give up? That it&#39;s safe to just give in, to move on, and forget what happened. To realize that the fight just isn&#39;t worth it. That there is another life through the fog of war. At what point? Tell me, I need to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there no one there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course not.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Death Cult</title>
    <link href="/2020/death-cult/"/>
    <updated>Tue Sep 08 2020 19:00:00 GMT-0500 (Central Daylight Time)</updated>
    <id>/2020/death-cult/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;9 September 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bradfrost.com/blog/link/the-american-death-cult/&quot;&gt;The American Death Cult&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does not go far enough. It is in no way just a &amp;quot;small, extremist death cult&amp;quot;. It goes beyond that in so many ways that COVID shows only the tip of the problem. The worldwide death cult is a pandemic that infects the hearts of millions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Boastful</title>
    <link href="/2020/boastful/"/>
    <updated>Thu Sep 10 2020 19:00:00 GMT-0500 (Central Daylight Time)</updated>
    <id>/2020/boastful/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;11 September 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.osb.org/rb/text/rbejms3.html#7&quot;&gt;Benedict&lt;/a&gt; and the book of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=James+3&amp;amp;version=NIV&quot;&gt;James&lt;/a&gt; repeatedly pounds into my head the dangers of boastfulness. That humility cannot include such a desire to be recognized for the deeds one does. It should not be for glory that a person does their work. It is certainly not my strength or will that accomplishes anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be frustrating not to be recognized for what you have done and just as frustrating not to be even heard in the first place. However, isn&#39;t that just pride? Who am I that makes me so great that I think I know the complete answer (see Dunning-Kruger). Moreover, who am I that thinks I should be heard in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is not to say it is easy to be silent or humble. The temptation is still there. The frustration. The &amp;quot;Me&amp;quot; society pulls us into their destruction and I find myself trying to fight against it often, wrongly, alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two examples that have recently helped me. The first person is &amp;quot;Dee&amp;quot;. He did many first-of-the-kind things in his life and was stabbed in the back. That ruined his vision of making the world a better place. He was humble, even after that experience, and continued on teaching people about his ideas and methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second person is &amp;quot;Tee&amp;quot;. He did many first-of-the-kind things in his life and was stabbed in the back. That ruined his vision of making the world a better place. He continually talks about all the things he was the first to do, tries to get his software to come to life, and talks about how he wants to be remembered. He wants to be remembered by his ideas, terms coined, and inventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which person would you rather be like? I wonder if it is a person&#39;s perspective on death. Whether you are religious or not does not make a difference whether you are afraid of death. I know people who know God and are not afraid of death and those who are. I know people who do not believe in God who are not afraid of death and those who are. It seems the person who is afraid of death wants to remind people what they have done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who are afraid of death want to be remembered for their accomplishments and not by who they were. You can argue that we are our accomplishments. Perhaps to an extent, but is that all that makes us who we are? What makes us think we should even be remembered?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title></title>
    <link href="/2021/TEMPLATE/"/>
    <updated>Tue Mar 02 2021 18:00:00 GMT-0600 (Central Standard Time)</updated>
    <id>/2021/TEMPLATE/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;3 March 2021&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>